Downloaded @ subs4free.club
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
And roll sound, please.
All right,
so just be thinking of anything
you'd like to include
while we set up.
We'll be ready to get started
in just a minute.
All right.
Do you know
anything about his parents?
A few things.
Good, because we couldn't
find anything,
and we also couldn't find any
military records for a Mickey Kelley.
Yeah. Well,
there's a reason for that.
Which is?
How much time you got?
As long as it takes.
We're rolling.
Okay, just start by
telling us how you two met.
I met Mickey Kelley later on in our
lives, back in 1991,
when he had just gotten back
from Desert Storm.
He retired from the Marines.
I was working at a
restaurant called El Patio.
I was valeting cars.
Mick was just a customer,
when this asshole cut in line,
ordered me
to get his ride first.
When I said no,
he started calling me names.
Shit like "beaner", "taco."
Little fight broke out.
Before I knew it, Mick jumped
in, pulled the guy off me,
but the guy
had friends with him.
I tried to help, but...
Fuck.
Mick had it under control.
He wiped the floor
with all of them.
Crazy thing was,
he never threw a punch.
And that was it.
It was over.
I thanked him.
And afterwards, I went around,
got his piece of shit car,
brought it to him.
And then that dude,
he looked me right in the eye,
and he said,
"Thanks a lot, Taco."
Now I saw
what this guy could do,
but I just had
to fuckin' ask him...
"What did you just call me?"
And I think he was a little
surprised by my tone, but he said,
"Hey, sorry, man.
I thought them
was your friends
and they was
calling you Taco."
After that, he just broke
out into the biggest grin...
and he became the best
friend I ever had.
Was Mickey Kelley really
that amazing of a fighter?
People seem to think that
the Holy Grail of MMA videos
is the Rickson Gracie
versus Yoji Anjo fight.
But it's not.
It's Kelley versus Blaine.
And people think
that it didn't happen?
That just makes me laugh.
'Cause I was there.
It all happened
back in the early '90s,
before the sport
even had a name.
- Yeah.
- Water?
- Thank you
- You are welcome.
Did you see this article?
I'm thinking maybe
a pink one or a blue.
Here's your water.
So when we got
to the airport,
- they told us our flight was overbooked.
- Thank you.
Which left only one open seat
in first class.
And I wanted my husband
to have that,
'cause it supports his back
a lot better.
Well, I just had to ask,
'cause for a minute there
I thought he was upset
'cause I was bad company.
No,
and it may seem very silly,
but I miss him.
We're on our way to Dubai to celebrate
our 50th wedding anniversary.
- That's where we met.
- Oh, wow.
Wow, 50 years.
Congratulations.
Since our last child
left for college,
we haven't been apart more than
four or five hours at a time.
Wow.
Maybe the person sitting next to
him would swap chairs with you.
Excuse me.
Pardon, sir.
Do you happen to know
who's seated in the chair
next to you?
A real nice young lady
and she's heading
back that way.
Is that right?
I appreciate it, sir.
Thank you.
- Hi.
I, uh...
Shit, um...
You're
in seat 5F, right?
Yeah.
Look, I know it's...
I know it's a long shot,
but any possibility
you'd be willing to trade...
Relax. I already told Mrs.
Miller I'd give her my seat.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we will be serving dinner...
So, uh, you, uh...
You gals in some sort of
beauty pageant or something?
No, no.
We're, uh...
We're doing
this modeling shoot
for this new fur company
in Dubai.
You're a fashion model.
No, well, it's my...
It's my first time.
The, uh...
the law office I work in,
they represent
this modeling agent
and he was nice enough
to give me the opportunity.
- Oh, okay.
- Mm-hmm.
So you... you a lawyer?
I'm a paralegal,
actually,
but it's kinda just like
a backup plan.
- A backup plan.
- Mm-hmm.
So what's the...
what's the main plan then?
To be a stay-at-home mom.
Well, once I meet my
husband, of course.
What? Why are you
looking at me like that?
No, no, you just...
you just don't
hear that every day.
That sounds good.
So what about you?
What brings you to Dubai?
I'm-I'm...
I'm just going to teach.
Teach what?
Uh, combatives.
It's like martial arts.
Specifically, the martial art's
called jiu-jitsu.
It's-it's
a Brazilian variation.
Is it like karate?
No, ma'am,
it's nothing like karate.
It's... Uh, to the layman
it would look like, uh...
- Olympic wrestling.
- Uh-huh.
The only difference being,
you get your opponent
to concede either
physically or verbally
by chokes, joint locks,
bone manipulation, stuff like that.
God, it sounds horrible.
No. No, no, no,
it's not-not horrible.
It's easy. I mean,
if something goes wrong,
- they tap and the match is over.
- Yeah.
- It's relatively safe. It's not...
- Really? It's safe?
Well, what...
What happened to your eye, then?
Okay, well,
that-that was an accident.
I mean, that... Normally,
things like that don't happen.
So you teach
real fighting, huh?
Yes, ma'am.
You know, I gotta say, I...
I do not like fighting.
I don't like watching it.
When I was a kid, my, uh...
my cousin got into it
with this other boy,
and both ended up all bloody
and it was awful.
I'll never forget it.
Well, if it makes you
feel any better,
I-I don't train to start fights,
just end them if I need to.
I guess that makes me feel
a little bit better, yeah.
Well, good. Good.
I'm Mickey, by the way.
- Layla.
It's very nice
to meet you, Layla.
It's nice
to meet you too.
Oh, my God.
Did I drool on you?
I'm so sorry.
It's... It's okay.
It's okay.
I didn't have the heart
to wake you up, so...
Oh, my God.
Did we land already?
We did, yeah.
I need to... I need
to get back with the group.
There's a shuttle
picking us up.
I'm at the, uh, Scorpione Hotel.
Layla Boudreau.
- Look me up.
- I will.
Shit.
Write it down.
Don't screw this up, son.
Welcome.
First of all,
I'd like to thank you all
for joining me here today.
And a really big thanks
to Amin's father
for facilitating this lesson.
He flew me out all the way from
the United States of America
to talk about something
I am very passionate about.
Maybe that passion
will become contagious,
and you all will adopt it
into your lives as I have mine.
I had the opportunity to learn Brazilian
jiu-jitsu straight from the source,
so I will do my best
to pay homage to my sensei,
Professor Renzo Gracie.
So let's get started.
So I will need a volunteer.
Who wants to help me out?
Amin, please,
join me up front.
I really appreciate
the opportunity, sir,
so thank you.
Thank you very much.
Thank my son.
He is the one
who introducing me
to this Brazilian jiu-jitsu.
Well, he is
an excellent student.
Very eager to learn,
as well.
He's eager to learn
to defend himself
against his big cousin.
Right.
Mr. Kelley, tell me,
if you are as good
as he says you are,
why do you not fight?
Well, there's plenty
of times in life
when you're forced
to fight as it is.
You know, I do my best
to not supplement
that number, you know.
Then why do it at all?
It's helped me.
Changed me, even.
Been a... sort of medicine
for me in a lot of ways.
- I see.
- Plus, I think everybody needs
a little meritocracy
in their lives.
And a jiu-jitsu match
is just that, you know.
Once you clap hands and go,
there's no hiding.
That mat is gonna
expose every lie
and confirm every truth
with each roll.
It truly holds
a mirror up to you,
right in your face,
every single day.
And I love that about it.
Um, I'm sorry, sir.
I just recognize
a friend of mine.
Would you... Could I just
briefly go say hello?
Of course, please.
Be right back, sir.
Layla.
- Hey.
- Mickey. Hi.
Hi, it's, um...
It's good to see
a friendly face.
Yeah, I, uh...
I looked for you
at the hotel,
but they didn't
have your name.
Yeah, um, they put all of us
under the host's name.
He's some Greek fur magnet,
I don't even... I can't even
pronounce his name.
Is everything okay?
- 'Cause you seem upset.
- Well...
Miss Layla.
You must return to the table
and apologize right away.
- He deserved it.
- Miss Layla, in Dubai,
a woman does not touch
a man, let alone strike him.
But he's allowed to
touch me all he wants
- wherever he wants?
- You misunderstand the customs here.
You've caused him
tremendous embarrassment.
I don't care if he's
embarrassed, he deserves it.
If Mr. Kostopoulos wants to
discuss modelling work over drinks,
then you must oblige.
Please, return
to the table right now,
or you'll be
in breach of contract.
Listen, buddy, I'm sure
we can work something out here.
Who are you, sir?
Just a friend
of hers. Why?
What do you do in Dubai?
Work for Sheikh Bin Khalid.
Ah, you're employee
of His Highness.
What do you do?
Kitchen supervisor?
Dog walker?
Secretary?
No, sir.
I teach jiu-jitsu.
Ah, yes.
Alvah here,
he doesn't like jiu-jitsu.
Why do you not like it?
I forget.
It's for, uh,
how you say?
Faggots.
Look, Mickey,
don't worry about me,
I'll-I'll take care of it.
I-I don't want to cause you
any trouble, okay?
Yes, Mr. Mickey,
please go.
Allow me to have a
conversation with my employee.
Do you wanna talk
to this guy?
I'll be fine.
I'll be sitting
right over there.
Layla, please,
come and sit.
We must have a discussion.
So I see you met
Dimitris Kostopoulos.
My cousin helped him start
a tiny fur market.
Now he basically runs
the entire trade.
One of the wealthiest
non-Emiratis in the city.
Do you know the girl?
Yes, sir. I-I just met her
on the flight over, but...
She's a prostitute.
- No, sir. All due respect...
- It is the truth.
Dimitris likes to hire
beautiful Western women
and pay them $50,000 to come here and
model for his private line of fur.
And when they get here,
they are encouraged to do more,
and they always say yes.
You see
his bodyguard, Alvah?
Ex-Spetsnaz.
Also an Israeli martial arts
expert in, um... Krav Magoo.
It's Krav Maga, sir.
- Excuse me?
- It's-it's... Krav Maga.
Dimitris says he has killed
eight people with his bare hands.
Would you pardon me
one more time, sir?
Excuse me.
So here's
how it goes.
If you do not apologize
to Mr. Kostopoulos
and spend a little time
with him,
we will de-fund
your return ticket
and you can find your own way
back to the United States.
You know, sir,
I can't help but feel like you
might have been trying to insult me
with the stuff about the dog
walker and the kitchen supervisor.
Or did I take that
the wrong way?
'Cause if you want to insult me,
just have the courage to do it, sir.
Don't hide it behind words that
could be taken more than one way.
Look, I don't know
who the hell
- you think are you are...
- Stelios.
Do you know who I am?
No, sir, I don't.
I just know
I don't like you very much.
Layla, would you
like to leave?
You're making me very upset,
and when I get upset,
Alvah gets very mad,
and he will be here
any second.
No, sir. I don't think
he's coming back.
Call a doctor, quickly!
Salaam
aleikum, Mr. Kostopoulos.
Is my friend
troubling you?
No.
I think it's time
we go, Mickey, no?
Please, give me a moment
and I will meet you in front.
Yes, sir.
Now, I could not hear
what you were saying,
but I do recognize
that look.
So let me tell you this.
Mr. Kelley is my friend.
And I know you're a friend
of my cousin,
but he has many.
I do not.
You are a guest here.
Don't forget that.
Your Excellency,
please believe me when I tell you,
I meant no disrespect
to you here in your home...
Stop it, Mickey.
I insist you stay here
one more week
and teach me
Brazilian jiu-jitsu.
I'd-I'd be happy
to get you started, sir.
I'm flattered, actually.
But could you possibly do me
one huge favor?
Could you get her
the first flight home?
Done.
Hello.
Hey, good afternoon.
Are you friend
of Mickey Kelley?
Maybe.
Who's asking?
I'm Layla.
I met him
a few weeks ago in Dubai.
I was hoping I could
get a hold of him,
but I didn't...
I didn't get his number.
But he, um...
He mentioned this shop.
And he...
and he told me about you.
Told you about who,
specifically?
You. You know, he said that
you were his-his best friend.
He give you a name?
Okay, um, this is what
he said it was: Taco?
Oh, my God. I am...
I am... I'm so sorry.
I shouldn't...
I shouldn't have come here.
Hey, I'm just kidding.
I'm totally just kidding.
I'm Taco.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
He called me yesterday.
He sounded jet-lagged.
He was supposed
to be here an hour ago,
but he hasn't shown up yet.
Oh.
Did he mention me?
Uh... no.
Yeah, okay.
I, um... I gave him
my number, but I guess...
I guess I shouldn't have
assumed that he...
Don't tell him
I came here, okay?
I'm-I'm feeling a little bit
embarrassed by all of this.
There he is.
Now he shows up.
Oh, my God, now he's gonna think
I'm some stalker, or something.
What... No, what...
What's going on?
If he wanted to talk to me,
he would've called.
I think I just misread
all of it.
- Please, just don't tell him I'm here.
- Taco?
- Please.
- Hold on.
- Hey, bud.
- Hey.
Good of you
to finally join me.
Sorry I'm late, man.
I-I overslept.
I'm still pretty...
pretty jet-lagged
- from the trip, you know.
- How was it?
I met a girl.
An Arab chick?
No, no, no, she's-she's
from North Carolina.
- She's...
- Okay, white girl.
Yeah, she's fucking
beautiful, man.
And, uh... I-I got
her phone number.
You know,
she wrote it down
and it-it was on the nightstand
right in the hotel,
and I looked at it every night
before I went to bed.
And then the night before
my flight to come home,
it's gone, you know.
But I told her about you.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, I told her about the shop.
- Hmm.
- But, I mean...
Fuck, she's probably... She's probably
waiting for me to call, you know.
- Yeah, maybe.
- You know, Taco, I've never believed
in that "love at first sight" crap
they talk about in the movies.
It's like you say about music,
that it's in the bottom end.
- Yeah.
- Brother, she fell asleep
with her head on my chest
for five hours,
and I couldn't move,
but I felt her heart, brother.
And it's strong, man.
It's got that bass
you talk about like...
Easy, bro.
You sound like an infatuated
little bitch right now.
Any chick hears you
talking like that,
they're gonna totally
fuckin' own your ass.
Taco, I would marry
this girl.
- Hey...
- I would marry her, I swear to God,
and I knew it after
knowing her ten minutes.
You know, you hear people
talk about "the one."
- Okay...
- She's mine.
Let's go eat, man.
I'm fucking starving.
You're not even
listening to me.
Totally am, bro.
Let me just get my wallet.
- Whoa, sorry about that.
- I'll be in the car.
I was not expecting him
to be such a... sissy about it.
Hey. You okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
I, um...
I never, um...
I've never heard anyone
say about me
exactly what I feel
about them, you know?
She left her number,
and I gave it to him
the next day.
Hey.
I thought I may have
missed you or something...
That was it.
Those two were fucking
inseparable after that.
Layla got a job
as a paralegal.
Excuse me,
guys. Pardon.
Mickey continued bouncing
at this local bar
and training when he could.
There weren't any standalone
jiu-jitsu schools back then,
so Mick and some other guys just
rented some space at a McDojo.
- McDojo?
- Yeah, like, you know,
some other places you go to
and order chicken nuggets,
and you get that real chicken,
but then you go to Mickey D's,
and what you're gettin'
- isn't even real.
- I get it.
I married them myself,
in bay number two of my shop.
So now, by the power
vested in me,
in the name
of Jesus Christ,
I pronounce you
husband and wife.
- You may kiss the bride.
- Okay.
It was just us.
- Neither of them had...
- Thank you!
...any real family
to speak of.
I did the interior
for you guys.
I have
a surprise for you.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
What?
Close your eyes.
Okay.
Hold out your hand.
- Okay, why...
- Keep your eyes closed.
- Okay, okay, okay, okay.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You know, I never really
knew what I wanted.
But I do now.
I want my son to have
all the stuff I never had.
And I wanna start by making
sure he's got a godfather.
- Me?
- Of course you, man.
Come on, you're the best
friend I got on the planet.
Mickey'd been through
the foster system,
so he wanted to be sure there
was no chance
of that ever happening to his kid.
Hello?
Few months later,
he gets a call
from his friend in Dubai
after he'd seen
an early UFC event.
It's great to hear from you.
Who is it?
But this isn't
just grappling, right?
This is like a-a real dangerous
fight, like on TV?
Well, yeah, I mean,
it's-it's no holds barred.
I just... I don't understand,
like, why...
why did you never
fight in one of those before?
Honey, I've never really
had a reason, you know?
But this is 25 grand
just to show up.
And that's a downpayment
on a house for us.
And it's another 75 grand
if I win.
Babe, I don't...
I don't know if I...
Babe... I can win.
Mickey'd
been offered to compete
in an eight-man tournament
along with Marco Blaine.
Marco was a top contender for
the Vale Tudo Championship belt
and one of the best strikers
in the world.
Mickey was just a prodigy
in ground fighting.
I'd never seen him tap, and he rolled
with some of the best in the business,
like Pitt. That dude was
in the fucking Olympics.
You all right?
Uh, but this fight
wasn't gonna be on TV.
Now, if you remember
back in those days,
most states had banned
MMA fights,
because, uh, John McCain
and some other senators,
they thought
it was too violent.
Matter of fact, one of the first
American promoters, Dick Mason,
he went and testified
in Washington.
You're wasting your time
testifying.
Can't even call
that crap a sport.
The world's already got
real athletes.
Mankind's always been intrigued
with finding its best athletes.
We're a competitive species.
Hell, we've even
invented games
to try and measure a man.
McGwire and Sosa can park more
balls over a center field fence
than the rest of the planet.
Shaq can slam dunk
over almost anybody's head.
Hm. Mike Tyson can touch anybody's nose
without them even seeing him flinch.
Impressive, all of them.
But, uh, make no mistake.
Outside of the rule
of law...
they'd all be doing
my athlete's laundry.
In this sport,
there's no headgear, no gloves,
it's bare knuckles
on the side of your head.
The gloves are only there
to protect the hands,
and, in fact, only ensure
that the punching continues.
And as far as headgear,
although it prevents cuts,
the downside of that
is that it does allow
for repeated concussion
to the brain.
Sanctioning MMA fights
was kinda like...
It had us back up against a brick
wall, but, you know,
once that Pandora's Box
was open...
people were hungry for it.
So these rich Arab guys
started putting on
their own tournaments
in the desert, gladiator-style.
Literally just saying,
"I wanna see this guy and this guy fight,"
offering them money,
flying them out.
We all flew out to Dubai
for an event and I...
I was to be in the corner
with my best friend.
Breathe in for me.
Breathe out.
He was more than ready,
and there wasn't
any doubt in my mind
that if he got to fight Blaine
and he could get him
to the ground,
that he'd completely
annihilate him.
All is good.
- Okay, thank you very much, Doctor.
- You're welcome.
Hey, Doc.
I saw you
make a face just now.
Why'd you make a face?
There are eight men
in this tournament.
Seven of them have
a resting heart rate of 85.
One of them
has a rate of 42.
Your friend
is either very confident...
or very naive.
And the winner, Marco Blaine.
Next, we have Mickey
Kelley, from the United States.
And Tadashi Yamamoto,
from Japan.
Gentlemen, you may begin.
There you go!
That's right, hang on!
And our winner,
by submission,
at 54 seconds,
Mickey Kelley!
For the first match
of our semi-finals,
we have Mickey Kelley,
from the United States.
And Razak, from Nigeria.
Gentlemen, begin.
Nice.
There you go.
Bring him down.
There you go!
Let's go!
The winner, by submission, Mickey Kelley!
Everyone was hoping it would
come down to Marco and Mickey.
And they got their wish.
After Mickey's
first two fights,
Mickey was
heavily favored to win,
and not just by me.
For our main event, we have Mickey
Kelley, from the United States.
And Marco Blaine,
from Brazil.
Gentlemen, begin.
Mickey went down
immediately,
with his hand still reaching for
that handshake that was never coming.
We had an agreement...
that I wouldn't throw in the
towel unless he was unconscious.
Mick, I'm throwing the towel!
There was a pleading
in his eyes like...
I should have listened to her.
It was one of the most
vicious beatings
I'd ever seen in my life.
He was never even in the fight.
Mickey suffered a broken eye
socket and a detached retina.
He also had a partial
detachment in his right eye
and was at risk for losing
his sight altogether.
He would never be medically
cleared to fight again.
His son was born a month later,
on his 40th birthday.
And in a strange way, it couldn't
have happened at a better time.
And all the pain and the
depression he was going through,
it just... vanished
when Kyd was born.
The next few years there was
no more talk about fighting.
Just got a new job and
focused on being a dad.
They were getting by.
Until around late 1998,
when MMA was fighting to get
sanctioned in the US.
Red Dragon Dojo.
Yes, ma'am.
Yes, ma'am, I can get him.
Just one second.
Our sport was incorporating
rules and becoming legit,
going mainstream pretty quick.
But I knew
that sooner or later,
seeing the guy who took
so much from him
on all the magazine covers
would probably start
to get to Mick.
More commitment, Veronica.
Nice, Chelsea.
Hey, uh, Jimmy.
Yes, Michael! What?
Uh, it's your girlfriend.
What the hell
does she want?
All right, guys, keep it up.
I'll be right back.
What?
After pushing a broom
during the day,
Mick would pick up extra cash
by teaching private lessons
in the evening.
Okay, now nothing outside
of what I've already taught you,
but now I'm gonna
throw 'em at random.
Speed it up a little bit, okay?
You ready?
Fold the wrist first.
Good job.
Fold it first.
Palm over knuckles,
elbows together.
Yes! Beautiful,
beautiful, beautiful.
Nice! Good job,
good job, good job.
- Daddy's home!
- Hey.
Hi.
I think I remember
having a son
when I left for work.
I wonder where he is.
Hmm. Maybe he left
for college already.
Where are you,
little shit?
Daddy, can you tell me the story
about Mommy's famous chicken?
You want Daddy to tell you
that story again?
- Mm-hmm.
- That's a good story.
I wanna say it was 1492.
Oh. It was
a really long time ago.
Mommy and Daddy were sailing the
ocean blue with their friend Chris.
- Columbus? That one?
- I-I think that's... It rings a bell.
We were looking for
a place called America
'cause that's where
they were having
the chicken finger
world championships.
But we only had
one chicken left.
- Mommy says it's not true.
- It is true.
Mommy's just being humble.
Remember what Daddy says, "We never let
the world see us beating our chest"?
That's Mommy.
Well, Mommy appreciates how
much Daddy likes her cooking,
but that story... No.
But they are the best
chicken fingers in the world.
- Finish up your supper, dude.
- Mmkay.
- I love you, dude.
- Love you.
Hey.
What's going on?
You're working tonight,
aren't you?
Yeah.
Will you tell me
about him again?
- Saint Sebastian?
- Yeah, is he dead?
Well, he's not dead.
But he was shot full arrows
and left for dead.
But because of his incredible
fortitude and endurance,
he survived.
That's why he's the patron
saint of soldiers and athletes,
'cause he never once
gave up.
- Pretty cool, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
Let's say our prayers
and go night-night, okay?
Okay.
- Angel of God...
- My guardian dear,
to whom God's love
commits me here.
Watch over me
throughout the night,
and keep me safe
within your sight.
Amen.
Amen, dude.
Jerome.
- No!
- Gentlemen.
- Don't touch me!
- How's everybody doing over here?
We're doing all right.
How can I help you?
Can I ask you gentlemen to move
to the other end of the bar?
Happy to buy you
a couple rounds on me.
I think I'm pretty comfortable
right here.
- Yeah.
- I understand that,
but if I can't get you
to the other end of the bar,
I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
I don't wanna do that.
We want everybody
to have a good time.
Thank you.
These guys won't stop...
- Ma'am.
- ...hitting on my boyfriend.
- Shut up, you stupid bitch.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa...
No, no, no...
Fuck's sake, Jerome!
- Sorry, Mick.
- Get 'em out!
Fuck!
I knew it was
gonna happen sooner or later.
I never wanted you
to go back to that job.
Baby, there were two of them, and fucking
Jerome wasn't even paying attention.
It doesn't ma... You know what
every single doctor has said.
You could lose that eye.
It's the only time it's happened
in the last two years.
I got to keep bouncing
until I can
build my student base.
There's no other way
to pay for Kyd's school.
Well, there are
plenty of other preschool...
Yeah, cheaper, not better.
I wanna give y'all
the better stuff.
Look, babe, I could just go back to the law
office then, if that's what we need to do.
What, then we're gonna earn money
to pay somebody else to raise Kyd?
- No, we're not doing that.
- Bouncing is not a risk
that you should be taking.
I get in a car every day,
don't I?
That's a risk. Come on.
That's not the same thing.
No, don't-don't do this.
Mm, this-this-this
isn't just about money.
I can see it in your eyes.
This is about you
needing to satisfy
this-this-this
competitive urge it is,
or whatever it is,
that you call it.
You want a fight.
You we re looking
for a fight!
Don't leave.
Come on.
Again?
Yeah.
I see, I'm walking up now.
I mean,
if I had some more students for privates,
I wouldn't have to bounce.
But they all want
an instructor
who will roll hard with
them occasionally, you know?
And actually throw.
She's not gonna be
okay with that.
Well, Mick, your doctor said
that you really shouldn't.
Come on, the doctors are
exaggerating, you know?
They're just trying to protect
themselves from lawsuits.
I-I got hit the other day,
nothing happened. C'mon.
We know a little hard rolling's
not gonna hurt anything.
Maybe you could try
doing something
where you don't have to get hit
in the face on a daily basis.
Jiu-jitsu's
all I know, Taco.
It's the only thing
I'm good at, man.
I spent my whole life trying
to build a value to society
in hopes that someday I could
trade little bits of it.
Maybe get some money
to someday start a family,
and I-I can't lose that.
Without that,
I'm-I'm-I'm mediocre, man.
And I'm scared shitless
of being mediocre.
These two were
hysterical.
Mick wouldn't even
make it past midnight
because Layla would come
and get him every time.
They couldn't be mad at each other
for more than a couple of hours.
- Let's go home.
- Mm...
Mr. Kelley?
Yeah.
We saw this fight on TV,
and this one guy,
he did this move.
I was wondering if you
could show it to us.
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
When your neck is inside
this triangle right here,
when I apply pressure,
it's actually gonna
collapse the carotid artery.
It restricts the blood flow
to the brain,
and your training partner's gonna
either have to ask you to stop,
or he's gonna go unconscious.
So, now just-just
get your hand ready,
- and when you feel it, you tap, okay?
- Okay.
- You ready?
- Uh, yeah.
Okay, here we go.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Can't you cause
brain damage?
No, I mean, only if you hold the
choke
well after your training
partner goes to sleep,
but we're gentlemen, I mean,
we-we don't act like that.
That's horrible.
Belly down's even worse.
So you hide
his hands underneath him.
Then your training partner
doesn't even have
the opportunity to tap.
It's not the nicest thing
in the world to do, but, uh...
I'll have to remember that next time I
find myself with a dude between my legs.
Josh, what are you doing?
Uh, thinking about
learning how to grapple.
I mean, all the MMA guys
use some form of it.
At least the guys who win.
Their rules
favor ground fighters.
Many techniques not allowed in
MMA, like bites, eye gouges,
can easily stop
a grappling attack.
Listen, Jimmy,
he-he just asked me
to show him a position.
I meant no disrespect.
I don't know why
you keep wasting your time
with the gay
wrestling shit.
Guys, let's
get out of here.
What I'm teaching keeps them
on their feet
and their opponents
on the floor.
I know, I understand.
Yeah, but what if someone surprises
you from behind, takes you down?
Well, Josh,
it depends on the type of attack.
If he tries from the back,
I have elbows to the face.
Or if he tries to tackle me from
the front,
I drop elbows right on his
spine, or I could box his ears.
Whatever.
Yeah, that would, uh...
that would probably hurt.
Oh...
You-you don't think
it'd get you off me?
- I didn't say that, Jimmy.
- Huh, old man?
Why don't we try it?
Hm? Why don't we try it?
Come on.
You're gonna stand there,
and you're gonna tell my students
that my techniques
don't work?
Glove up and prove it.
I'm not telling your students
anything, Jimmy.
- Okay?
- Hey, no one has to get hurt.
Soon as you were to stop,
just, you know, tap out.
You're used to that, right?
Gentlemen,
it's time to go.
I got a lot of cleaning to do
before class tomorrow. Let's go.
- Come on, Mick.
- Now! Come on.
Choke.
- Let's go, guys.
- Come on, Mick.
What, are you afraid of
a little demonstration?
I'll see you tomorrow.
What are you doing?
You wanna know what I teach?
I'll show you what I teach.
- You wanna know why I think what you teach is garbage?
- Hey, guys.
I'll show you that, too.
Hell, I'll even give you
a roadmap
as to what's gonna happen.
I'm gonna close
the distance to clinch
without so much
as taking a scratch.
I'm gonna take you to the
ground, I'm gonna mount you,
I'm gonna turn you over,
take your back,
and I'm gonna choke you
unconscious.
And then just so you don't
think it was a fluke,
we're gonna do it
all over again.
And I'm gonna do
the exact same thing
in the exact same order,
and there's not a goddamn
thing you can do about it.
Okay.
You just know
if you get too close,
I'm throwing for real.
What is going on?
I'm throwing
with bad intentions.
Okay, pal.
Let's rock.
Son of a bitch.
- Oh, fuck you!
- Whoa. Did you see that?
Fuck you! Let's go
again, pal! Come on!
Let's go!
Come on! Bring it!
Shit, shit, shit!
Daddy's home!
- Hi, Daddy!
- Hey, dude.
- I am armed.
- Mm...
No, you're not. You're unarmed.
What has gotten into you?
He's watching TV.
All I had to do was
log on to one of those forums.
But nobody was online
that much back then.
I mean, shit, we still had dial
up, if you can remember that.
Anyway...
Turns out some interesting stuff went
down in Dubai a few months earlier.
So what do you
think would be a real challenge?
I don't have
any real challenge out there.
I run this division.
All my fights the same:
I win, I win, I win.
This guy don't try to win.
- He just tries to survive...
- Fuck you, man!
- Whoa!
- I'll take you on right now! Come on!
- Right now!
- Get the fuck off my stage!
Well, maybe Mr. Mason
would be a good challenger,
but it's never a good idea
to fight your boss.
What are you
so mad about, Amin?
He's the best.
Show respect.
It's manipulated
to give him easy wins.
Why doesn't he fight
Miletich then?
Miletich would mangle him.
No, Blaine's punches
are fucking dangerous, man.
Whatever.
He's a cheater, anyways.
Oh, so he's
a cheater now, huh?
I'll show you.
Wait, what?
Your dad has tapes
of his tournaments?
Yeah, I found them a few months ago.
He used to keep them in a safe,
- but now they're just...
- Who's this big guy?
He looks badass.
White dude's
gonna get ass-raped.
Oh, yeah? He was my
instructor when I was a kid.
Ooh.
Oh, shit.
You think that guy
could beat Blaine?
Mickey Kelley!
Again, watch.
...we have Mickey Kelley,
from the United States.
- And Marco Blaine, from Brazil.
- No way.
When was this?
Gentlemen, begin.
Wait a minute.
- Was he still bowing?
- Yep.
Dude, we gotta show
my brother.
He thinks Marco's a god.
When's he back from London?
I'll just upload it
to my site.
He wasn't even looking!
- What? That's bullshit.
- Back it up.
Bloody hell.
We should post it in the forum.
I'll bet it'll get like 1,000 views.
- Squash it.
- Pointless.
It's been uploaded and ripped
a dozen times over.
Oh, get out of here.
You can hardly see
either of them
from the distance
of this video.
This thing could be a work.
It wasn't a work.
This guy's good.
And that is
clearly your boy.
Let me tell you something.
There is always some backyard
theoretical fighter
who thinks he can
take on the pros.
They never succeed,
they never will.
So bring me somebody else
besides some fucking journeyman.
Your number one contender's
on a six-month
damage suspension.
You asked me who I thought
would be the biggest draw.
Now you log on
to any one of these forums,
and you'll see that there's a
ton of buzz around this video.
So you want to give
some nobody a title shot
because he got
sucker-punched by Blaine,
what, six years ago?
Jesus, the clown's lucky that
Blaine ended him so quickly.
You should watch
the whole video.
'Cause this guy's
no journeyman.
He is the real deal.
- Oh, says who?
- People. People that know.
And they're saying that Marco's
claim to being undefeated
is hollow
because of this fight.
And as soon as this hits the
magazines, it's inevitable.
Everybody's gonna want
to see a rematch.
Right?
This is a story.
This is the kind of story
that dream fights
are made of.
I don't finance
people's dreams.
I finance their do's.
Okay.
Well, this isn't his dream.
He doesn't even
know about it.
I don't even know
if he would accept the fight.
Dude just kinda
disappeared one day.
Who is he?
His name's Mickey Kelley.
Pitt knows him.
Personally,
I-I felt sorry for him, man.
I mean...
I mean, hell, had to be
like 40-something when I
caught back up with him.
And you-you can't just go
that many years
without high level training
and expect to be competitive.
You know, I mean,
at least not against anybody who's good.
So, um, you know...
Jiu-jitsu
constantly evolves,
and that's exactly
what I told Mason,
but, you know, he insisted.
Hello?
Mick.
Is that Pitt?
Yeah.
How you doing?
Good, brother.
How you doing, man?
- Good. It's good to see you.
- You too, man.
What the fuck you
doing here, man?
You know,
paying some bills.
- You know?
- Yeah, okay.
Hey, I heard
about the new gym.
I'm, uh,
I'm proud of you, man.
Thank you,
thank you, thank you.
I knew you'd do something
with wrestling.
Shit, man.
So what's, uh...
What's going on?
- Travis, this is Mick. Mick, meet Travis.
- How are you, man?
- What's up, man? Nice to meet you.
- Very nice to meet you.
He's been training with me
for a little bit.
I'm looking to get him some
fights, I want him to get
some more different styles,
and I was telling him
that you was a slippery
motherfucker back in the day, so...
Well, I appreciate that, man.
I was just wondering if, um...
You mind rolling with him
a little bit?
See how he does?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Right-right now?
- I got my gear with me. I'm ready.
- If it's okay.
Yeah, we could, uh...
You want me
to grab the broom or...?
- No, that's-that's...
- Okay. All right.
- Let's go.
- Okay, let's go.
- You good?
- Uh, yeah.
Yeah. Let's get it.
Let's get it.
Watch your neck.
Watch your neck. Watch...
Neck, neck, neck!
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm good. I'm good.
That's a good warm up.
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
- All right?
Hey.
Close the elbow.
Hey, close...
Close the elbow right there.
Watch your neck...
Neck, neck.
He's looking for the... neck.
Now, fight.
Watch the fade.
Nothing there. Nothing there.
A little hand play right here.
Uh-huh. Okay.
Uh-huh.
Beautiful shot, Travis!
Widen your base.
There you go!
Uh-huh. Yeah.
Ah, he's reaching under.
He's reaching under.
Mother...
Turn the corner.
Watch the arm.
Watch the ar...
Turn into him.
No. Breathe. No, no, you good.
He's going for the arm.
You all right?
Yeah. I'm good, man.
All right, Mick.
Give it to him straight.
You know,
I think you know
you leave your neck
dangling on that shot.
Uh, you know, on the single,
uh, run the pipe quick.
Uh, keep your elbows tucked just so I
can't get the Kimura grip figure-four.
I mean, this is nothing
that Pitt can't...
- Chicken wing.
- ...fix, you know. It's, uh...
I mean, you clean those up,
you'll be...
You'll be dangerous, buddy,
I promise you.
Yeah, maybe I'll do that.
- Thanks, man. I appreciate it.
- Of course.
- Pitt, I'll see you outside.
- Yeah.
Okay.
All right, TP.
Yeah, good train.
- Was that all right?
- You really don't know
what the fuck is going on
out in the world, do you?
What're you talking about?
Bro, that's
Travis Prince, man.
He just won
Brazilian nationals.
Like I asked you before...
What the fuck
are you doing here?
Oh, trust me,
he's still got it.
If he's injured,
I can't tell.
Really?
Don't say anything to him just yet.
Nope, I won't
mention it to him.
I'm actually thinking about
offering him a job,
so I don't want his head
to get too big if I do.
What do you mean?
What, you think
the guy's that good?
Well, I'll tell you what,
if you do end up putting
this fight together,
my money is not gonna be
on your boy.
What? Are you joking?
Yeah... Let me put it
this way.
If the fight goes to the
ground, your man is fucked.
You know
I would, man.
Yeah.
Hey.
What's going on?
So... you know,
let me, uh...
Let me talk to Layla about it,
and I'll-I'll call you tomorrow.
All right?
Okay. Talk soon.
Who was that?
You remember...
You remember Pitt, right?
Terry? Yeah.
Well, he started an MMA
training facility a while back,
and he'd like me
to teach grappling.
Baby, I wouldn't
have to bounce any...
I'm so sorry.
So am I.
Just promise me
you're gonna be careful.
- I will.
- Okay.
Watch the leg, though.
Watch the leg.
Hey, Pitt?
Pitt!
There he is.
What's up, brother?
Wow.
Welcome home, baby.
Welcome home.
When your opponent
switches base,
head side, he's on top.
There's two options, really.
Opponent's head's
going to be high.
So can you turn into me?
Now when I'm ready,
I'm gonna hip escape out,
and I'm gonna straighten
that table.
Table disappears...
and I come to the top position.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Beautiful.
Where do his hands go?
To his face.
This hand is solely there
to prevent me from closing
the distance to you.
Stop, stop,
stop, stop, stop.
Not for your face.
Guys, leverage and efficiency.
He's right over there.
Hey, yo, Mick.
Guys, excuse me
for one second.
- Dad!
- Dude!
I didn't expect visitors
on my first day of work.
What is happening
right now?
- Oh, choke! I tap out! Daddy taps out!
- Okay, okay.
Well, we wanted to come
and see Daddy's new office.
Thank you.
This is amazing.
Daddy thinks so, too.
I'm very excited
about this place.
Dad, when will I
get to fight?
Well, if everything goes
according to plan, never.
- Why?
- Hey.
Daddy's already taught you the
self-defense aspects of jiu-jitsu.
And that'll get you out of just about
any problem that comes up to you.
But you're not getting
in a ring or a cage.
Daddy wants you to have
other options in life.
All I learned is fighting.
And I wish I had
those options.
But I want you
to be different.
Mr. Pitt says kids
my age can fight.
Oh, is that
what Mr. Pitt says?
I-I don't really recall having that
conversation with you... whatsoever.
'Cause I think I recall having
a conversation with Mr. Pitt,
and telling him
"Not my kid."
- The kid would never fight.
- He... Never.
Yeah, so when-when
we were talking, that we...
You weren't supposed
to mention that, man.
I just had to.
I'll tell you what I'll do...
- Pitt, throw me the glove.
- Here.
Give me your hand.
Put it in here.
Right there.
Look at that.
When that fits,
we'll talk about it.
- You understand?
- Yes, sir.
And for a brief moment,
everything seemed okay.
But, eventually, that video
caught up with him.
It's me.
All right.
Call his manager.
If the guy's even got one.
Now he's gonna
take him down.
Textbook movement.
The winner,
by submission, Mickey Kelley!
That same day,
I got a call from Brian Burchman,
some big shot matchmaker.
He gave me a bunch of forums
to check out.
Sure enough, all the talk was
of Mickey being the only fighter
that could possibly
beat Blaine.
The public
was demanding a rematch.
But Mickey was 46 years old,
and out of training,
while Blaine was 31
and at the top of his game,
not to mention
the other problem.
Your boy's
becoming a legend.
He'd be stupid
not to cash in on this.
Yeah, but he might have
an issue with the physical.
He's got a bad eye.
Don't worry,
if he wants to fight,
I got a doctor for him.
Look, it doesn't matter
what I say,
I know he'll want the fight.
He's not the problem.
Babe, it's $75,000
just to walk in the ring.
It's more than I make
in a year.
I don't care if it's a million dollars.
I can't let you do it!
- Okay, could you just let me...
- No, for five years
I have felt guilty for letting
you do something so stupid.
Okay, I was young.
I thought I could win.
I'm older now,
I know I can't win.
I'll go there,
I'll roll around,
at the first sign of trouble,
I'll tap.
And we'll go home
with some money.
Do you really expect me to
believe that when you get there,
you can get in that ring
with that fucking prick
and you're going to be able
to resist the urge
to give him the ass-kicking
that he deserves?
Really? Really? Okay,
well, go ahead.
Look me in the eye,
and tell me that.
I can't.
I mean, when you met me,
I was great at something.
I was confident,
and I was proud,
and I had this thing that I
carried with me everywhere.
You take that away from me,
and I'm not the same.
I'm not even...
I'm not even a man anymore.
I had somebody like that
for a dad.
And I just don't
want that around Kyd.
I need to face him.
I do.
No. No.
I was barely okay
with him teaching privates,
but this-this is just...
Crazy? I know.
Privates don't always
try to hurt him,
but in-in a cage,
it's literally all they're trying to do.
- Maybe I can just...
- But I love him.
And it's a question
he needs answered, so...
If I don't let him do it,
it's going to eat away
at him forever.
He's gonna end up resenting me
and I will lose him anyway.
Now I know why
you two are married.
You're just as nuts
as he is.
Promise me
on your godson's head
that if I tell you
to stop the fight,
that you will
stop the fight.
Thank you.
Hey.
Okay.
Okay?
I love you.
- A lot.
- I know, me too.
Before he even had a contract,
Mickey started training his ass off.
Come on, let's hit it.
Let's go, Mick.
- You got this, baby.
- Put in that work, baby.
Put in that work.
Uh-huh.
Keep working.
All right, here's the reality
of the situation, Mick.
If you stand it with this guy. you got
a life expectancy of 60 seconds, okay?
The longer you're up,
the more chances you got of getting hit.
All right, brother?
Building strength,
building speed.
- All right, baby. Come on, push it.
- Come on.
You're gonna need
to close the distance
and take him to the ground
faster than ever.
And once he's down,
you don't have unlimited time
like you did in old days, man.
You got five minute rounds,
so you're gonna have
to submit him before the bell.
On top of that,
Marco's been working on his ground game,
so he's not the same
jiu-jitsu newbie.
We're gonna give you
the clinch strength
of a goddamn silverback, boy.
You hear me?
So that when you're
on the ground,
you're gonna manipulate him
like a Gumby doll.
Working on techniques
that would help his left side
get protected
as much as possible...
Forget the hill drop, okay?
Don't worry about taking
his back or nothing like that.
Blaine knows you're a grappler, okay?
He's expecting that.
Take him over the top.
Suplex.
...while trying new
strategies keep Blaine on his toes.
But it was all pointless.
Begin.
Mason
had fought so hard
to bring the sport
to the mainstream...
that he couldn't risk having
a fighter get massacred on TV.
So before officially
announcing the fight,
he brought in a real doctor
for Mickey's physical.
Mickey passed everything with flying
colors up until the vision test.
There was no way Mick
was getting cleared.
That was March 8th, 2001.
His car was at my shop
with a bad carb,
so I dropped him off
at the doctor's.
Layla was gonna pick him up.
Me and Kyd were
coming back from Hobby Shack.
Grandma! Grandma Taco!
Look what Uncle got me!
- ...ran a stop sign...
- 6:00 p.m.
...crashing into
a Volkswagen Beetle.
I actually saw it
on the news.
First responders
are on the scene.
Yeah.
Layla's death...
changed Mick
in a way that...
I'll never be able
to describe.
He never said it, but...
he felt responsible.
It was all over his face.
If only he hadn't...
Hey, dumbass! I'm talking to you!
Hey, man, you all right?
- No, I'm good. I'm-I'm going.
- You all right, brother?
Everything okay?
I think Kyd was the only
thing keeping him alive.
Remember to tell your mom
about the honor roll, all right?
- Okay.
- She's gonna be very proud of you.
And tell her
I had you try sushi, okay?
- Okay.
- You don't have to tell her you thought it sucked.
Keep that to yourself.
- Hey, dude.
- Oh, thanks.
Aren't you coming?
No, you know, I...
I came earlier today.
- Oh.
- So this is, uh...
- This is your time. You go. Okay?
- Okay.
And tell her you're gonna learn
how to surf this summer! Huh?
And that you love her.
That we...
That we love her,
buddy.
- Night-night, dude.
- Night-night.
What about our prayers?
Yeah.
Yeah, we can.
Angel of God,
my guardian dear,
to whom God's love
commits me here.
Watch over me
throughout the night,
and keep me safe
within your sight.
Amen.
You know, I really appreciate
how much you and your mom
have helped out with Kyd.
Come on, bro.
You're family.
How you holding up?
Feels like a fridge
fell on my chest, man.
Feel like my lungs just aren't
filling up properly when I breathe.
And I don't want Kyd to
see me like this, you know?
You're being
really hard on yourself.
It's a tough thing
you're going through.
You remember
what I told you about, uh...
about my dad?
Yeah, he walked out on you.
Killed himself.
Right after
he killed my mom.
Life gave him
a couple hard knocks
and he took it out on us.
I guess he couldn't...
provide for us, you know?
So he just... he just...
He fuckin' gave up.
And he took
my mom with him.
And I'm...
I'm fucking ashamed
of that, man.
When I got out of the
military, you know,
I-I took my mom's
maiden name, legally.
I wanted to throw away everything
about that fucking O'Sullivan name.
I wanted nothing to do
with anything that he was.
Why are you
telling me this now?
'Cause I need you
to know who I am.
And I don't want Kyd to see that
same defeat in my eyes, you know?
I want him to know
the Kelleys keep fighting.
We don't stop.
You know...
A good dad is not
supposed to tell his son
how to live his life,
you know?
He's just supposed
to live it correctly
and let him watch.
And I know he's watching, man.
I just never...
planned on doing this
without her, you know?
Listen...
You're gonna
get through this.
I promise.
- God doesn't give you...
- Don't, man.
Just don't...
don't bring up God.
I got some fuckin'
words for him.
That's what Layla
would say if she was here.
Remember that time she showed
up at my place crying...
'cause you told her you
were gonna take the fight?
You know
what she said to me?
No. What?
Was that the moment
that you got into that ring,
and you looked that son
of a bitch in the eyes...
He's gonna know he can win,
and he's not gonna stop until he does.
Guys. Gi's on, belts on.
Class starts in five minutes.
Hey, Mick.
Hey, uh...
Hey, listen, I, uh...
I heard about your wife.
I'm sorry, man.
I'm really sorry.
Look, if you
ever need anything...
I mean it.
I-I appreciate that.
Yeah. Okay.
Jimmy.
What are you doing here?
Well, I've been going over
what you did to me on the mat
for the past few years,
and I, uh...
Well, I just... I can't wrap
my head around it.
So I signed up
for your evening class.
I'll be seeing you.
Yo, Mick, phone call.
Hey, Pitt,
can you take a message?
Well, he says it's important.
Some dude from Dubai.
Some time in late July,
Mick got a call
from his old friend in Dubai.
Turns out, Dimitris found out about
the rematch that never happened
and offered to put it up
himself with the same purse.
Seventy-five grand
just to show up,
and another 150 grand
to the winner.
We got a fight.
Hey, who's the man of the
house while daddy's gone?
- I am.
- That's right.
So, anything Granny Taco needs,
you make sure she's okay.
Yes, sir.
And you be a gentleman,
and pay attention to her, okay?
- Okay.
- It's only five days.
So I'll be back
before you know it.
And you know what?
Daddy's flying again.
So maybe I'll talk
to the pilot
and see if I can
bring you back some wings.
I love you, dude.
I love you, too.
Needless to say,
after 30 days of hard training,
we were on a plane
headed right back to Dubai.
I couldn't believe Mason
even agreed to let
Blaine fight,
but I guess at his core,
he's just a fan
like the rest of us,
and, you know,
he wanted to see who'd win.
So, to keep it quiet,
he said 100 lucky witnesses max,
and that all attendees would have
their lips permanently sealed.
Ah! Welcome back to Dubai.
I appreciate the opportunity,
Mr. Kostopoulos.
Nice to see you again,
my friend.
Wonderful to see you
too, sir.
Again, thank you for the
hospitality with my friend.
Think nothing of it, Mickey.
I would have thrown the fight myself
if I would've known
you'd still be interested.
Are you joking?
He is stubborn.
I saw it seven years ago.
Doesn't know
when he's beaten.
Now he comes here to risk
his health for only $75,000.
Is that the worth
of a man's health in America?
You care for a dollar
like I care for a million.
At least Marco,
he bargained with me a little bit.
I got him for 100,000,
and when he wins the extra 150,000,
he's going to buy
a Ferrari Maranello.
This is what you are to him,
a new car.
Ah! He is also ready.
Mick, you good?
Yeah, I'm good.
Weighing in at 168 lbs,
Mickey Kelley!
Yeah, baby.
And his opponent...
weighing in at 170.9 lbs,
Marco Blaine!
They're talking
about you, champ.
- Okay.
- No.
These are the terms,
as agreed to by both camps.
First, there will be no
biting, no headbutts.
Mr. Kostopoulos
is taking wagers,
if you are so inclined,
gentlemen.
- I am so inclined. You?
- Yeah.
...if the opponent
has a hand on the mat.
Anything else you need,
princess?
Maybe some knee pads.
What's up?
Okay, gentleman.
We will see you tonight.
Bin Khalid
thinks you are brave.
But I know the truth.
You are not brave,
you are stupid.
What really makes you
think you can win?
I'm gonna make him quit.
You see, God, or Allah,
or whatever
you want to call him?
He's got a message
for all athletes
that get pushed far enough,
and he delivers it
through lactic acid.
It's a by-product
of muscle use.
Hell, it makes standing
even almost unbearable.
It's his way of saying
that your organs
are gonna completely shut down
if you keep pushing yourself.
Well, your boy,
when God talks to him,
I'm bettin'
he's gonna listen.
And what about you?
I quit listening to God
six months ago.
- You ready?
- Yeah, let's get out of here.
See him? I see him.
What is it?
Kelley.
That's not his name.
And now, hailing
from the United States,
in only his fourth
professional fight,
Marine Corps veteran
and jiu-jitsu instructor,
Mickey Kelley!
How you doing, son?
Sit down. Sit down, here.
You're about to go to work.
I'm Dick Mason.
I'm the guy that, uh,
tried to put this fight
together the first time.
The right way.
Apologies.
Medical exam,
it was out of my hands.
Marine, huh?
I was a commanding officer
myself during the Gulf War.
I only lost one marine
under my eye the whole time.
That low number didn't
make it any better, though.
His Abrams rolled over
a pissant IED near Kirkuk,
the c-track de-wheeled.
He was an engineer,
just like myself when I enlisted.
He did his job to perfection.
He got out of that tank.
He almost fixed that shit...
'til a sniper found him.
Ear to ear.
Dropped him on the spot.
His best friend
since he was in boot
was in the tank with him,
a guy named O'Sullivan.
Crew was ordered to evac,
the whole battalion was re-routed.
When they came under
a gun and mortar fire,
everyone obeyed,
except for O'Sullivan.
You know, it turns out
you never know
what a man's capable of
until you look him in the eye.
But he waited there
for two days,
guarding his best friend's body
until it could be extracted.
Did it all with a sidearm,
a pistol, mind you.
A damn pistol.
When they asked him
why he did it after the fact,
he stood in front
of this debrief panel
under threat of a DD
and he told them,
"Because the job
wasn't done yet."
Really wish I could've
looked that fella in the eye
before I called that pull.
Now, once the story got out,
all the bigwigs
back in Washington,
they wanted to throw
a medal at him.
I wanted to meet him myself
for my own reasons.
But we couldn't find him.
Apparently,
he changed his name.
You ever hear
that story before, son?
I always wanted
to meet the man
that carried my son
off that field.
Semper Fidelis,
Sergeant O'Sullivan.
Godspeed.
Here we go.
We have it. We're good.
Whoo! He looks good.
He looks good!
We're gonna make
so much money
betting against these idiots!
Hell, Vegas is gonna die
for these odds.
Taco, look, wearing
a frickin' sherpa.
This is amazing, bro.
Rematch of the century.
Ladies and
gentlemen, welcome to the fight
that everyone asked for,
only made possible
- by the Pope of Al Nasser Square...
- Here you go, over here.
...Mr. Dimitris Kostopoulos.
Now, without further ado,
a man that needs
no introduction.
From Brazil, the undefeated VTC
welterweight champion,
Marco Blaine!
- Use your head.
- It's time, baby.
Use your head now, hmm?
Time to execute.
Come on.
His opponent,
hailing from the United States,
unknown to most,
but celebrated by many,
a jiu-jitsu fighter and US Marine
corps combatives instructor,
with only three known fights and a
record of two wins and one loss...
Mickey Kelley!
- Let's go to work, baby.
- All right, listen, Mick.
You're better than this guy.
I know that, and you know that.
You have nothing to prove.
If something
doesn't feel right,
let's get out of there
safe, okay?
So watch that thick skull
of yours.
I'm gonna go over there,
say hi to him.
Mick, Mick, Mick.
Oha, Mickey.
I wouldn't miss this.
Good luck, man.
Good to be here.
Professor Renzo.
I'm good.
Turn around, Mick.
It's time. Let's go.
Gentlemen.
You know the rules.
Obey me at all times.
Protect yourselves
at all times.
I want a clean fight.
Understood?
If you want to shake hands,
do it now.
To your corners.
Thirty seconds, bro.
If he doesn't get Marco
down in 30 seconds,
it's no good.
- Let's go, baby.
- All right.
- Go to work.
- He looks good.
Ready?
Begin.
- Yes!
- That's what you want!
That's what you want, baby!
Yes, sir!
Bring him down!
Protect, baby! Protect!
Yep. Here you go!
There you go, bring him...
bring him down!
Twelve seconds!
He got him down in 12 seconds!
Your world, baby!
Your world!
Make him pay!
Nice!
There you go!
Here we go!
- There you go, Mick!
- Give it to him! Give it to him!
Give it to him!
Yes! Yes, that's the sequence
right there. Yeah.
- Here we go!
- Yes, yes!
- Squeeze! Squeeze!
- Lock him! Lock him up!
Go! Go! Go!
Go! Go! Squeeze!
You got him!
He can't move! Break!
Break!
Whoa! What are you doing?
He had him!
- What are you doing?
- No headbutts.
Dammit,
the fight was over!
To your corners!
- This is bullshit!
- Go see your cornerman!
- Come here! Fucking pussy!
- He had him!
No wonder they didn't wanna be on camera!
Let me see your face!
- Hey, one warning only.
- You're fine.
You're fine.
He's good. He's good.
- You're good.
- You're good, Mick.
Next violation,
you'll be disqualified.
Fighters, ready?
No! Start him on the ground!
- Fighters, begin.
- On the ground!
No! No! No!
Dammit!
- Make him pay.
- Cover your face, Mick!
Get up, baby! Get up!
Get up!
Back away!
There you go!
- Come on!
- Get up!
- Really?
On your feet!
Fight.
- Defense.
- Cover up, Mick!
Cover up, Mick!
Mick, chin down!
Chin down, Mick!
Guard, baby! Guard!
Here it comes, baby!
- Yes!
- That's it, baby!
- He's hurt, baby! He's hurt!
- Yes! Yes!
Here you go!
Now he wants to take it
to the ground?
You see his legs buckle?
He rocked him, baby!
Yes, your world! Give it!
Work the guard right there,
that's right.
- Work the guard!
- Cover up, Mick!
- Control him! Posture!
- Cover up! Cover up!
Control
his posture, Mick!
Control that!
- Cover up, Mick!
- Defense!
Cover up, Mick!
Don't go! Don't go!
Defense!
Turn your head!
Get the hook!
Grab his arm!
There you go!
Keep it going!
You got it!
Turn him!
Go! Go! Go!
Stay-stay heavy!
Come on!
Triangle! There you go.
- Grab him!
- There you go!
- Turn him!
- Yes!
- There it is!
- Let's go!
- Nice! Nice!
- Very nice!
- Motherfuck!
- Break!
He looks really bad.
Shit.
You're good.
- What's wrong?
- He can't see. At all.
It's just white streaks.
Mick, we're gonna have
to throw in the towel.
We can't.
What do you mean, we can't?
Mr. Kostopoulos...
You know, I thought
about what you said.
You know, Marco wants a car.
Well, I want something, too.
I want a house and an
education for my kid.
That's nice,
but you cannot win.
You know, you say a dollar to me
is like a million to you.
I can't argue with that.
So I got
a proposition for you.
Why don't you
keep your 75 grand?
I'll show up
tomorrow for free.
But, if I happen to win,
you give me that million.
I trust your word's good?
Bin Khalid
thinks you are brave,
but I know the truth.
You're not brave,
you are stupid.
What really makes you
think you can win?
It's all or nothing.
You stupid fucking hick,
Mick!
I may have to eat
a few punches to get to him,
but if you can guide me to
him, I can submit him.
- Mick...
- Listen to me.
I had my head on his chest.
It's all tweeter.
There's no bass.
He's gonna quit.
I swear to God,
he's gonna quit.
All right,
you guys. Stool out.
I'm gonna guide you
through this thing.
But you're gonna have
to listen for my voice, okay?
Layla's gonna be for left,
Kyd's gonna be for right.
All right?
Three steps straight out.
Ready? Begin.
Hands up, baby.
Hands up. Hands up. Let's go.
Hands up, hands up,
hands up.
Hands up, baby. Hands up.
Layla. Layla. Layla.
Layla.
Layla. Layla.
Layla. Layla. Layla.
- Clear that space, baby.
- Here you go.
- Shit.
- Here comes another one.
- Distance, distance.
- Ah.
Clear that space, baby.
She's close. Attack. Attack.
Put those hands up, baby.
- Put 'em up. Watch it!
- Kyd, Kyd, Kyd, Kyd!
Hands up, Mick!
Attack.
Put your hands up, Mick.
Watch out, Mick!
Hands up! Hands up!
Close it!
He's closing it!
Stop him! Stop him! Stop him!
Okay. It's okay.
Kyd. Kyd. Kyd. Kyd.
Come on. Come on, Mickey!
- Up, up, up!
- Let's go, baby! Six feet away!
- Six feet away!
- On your feet.
- Breathe, baby, breathe.
- He's right in front of you.
Layla! Layla, Mick.
Come on, Mickey!
Get up, Mick.
Mick, I'm gonna have
to throw in the towel
if you don't get up.
Get up!
You gotta get up, Mick!
I love you a whole lot!
You love me.
What about our prayers?
Angel of God,
my guardian dear,
to whom God's love
commits me here.
Watch over me
throughout the night,
and keep me safe
within your sight.
I need to stop
this thing, Mick.
Hey, God bless you, Mick!
Come on!
- Cover up, Mick!
- There you go!
Come on!
Yes!
Take the back!
Why is he not taking the back?
He's taking him over the top!
Finish him, Mick!
Why is he not taking it?
He's hiding his hands
so he can't tap out.
Yes, fuck this guy, Mick!
Fuck him! Yes!
He's out! It's over!
The winner is Mickey Kelley!
Yes!
What the hell
you so happy about?
Wait, you changed your bet?
I looked in his eyes.
I haven't seen that kind of
conviction since Zaire 1974.
Get in there!
Get your man!
Mick, you did it!
Marco went back to
Brazil and never fought again.
Mickey... Mickey was
rushed to the hospital.
Doctors found cerebral swelling
due to the hits he took.
They had to induce a coma.
Where's my daddy?
Getting out
of that cab alone
was one of the most difficult
things
I'd ever done in my life.
If this
all really happened,
why did we never
hear about it?
The fight happened
on September 1st, 2001.
Ten days after that,
nothing really mattered.
You know, we went down
to Carvell cemetery,
and we saw Layla's grave,
but we didn't see Mickey's.
Hey, yo, Mick!
You got company.
Go ahead, man.
They fit.
Okay.
But we never start 'em.
We just finish 'em.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull